Mansi Patel

CONTACT

: mansi.patel@mail.com

2 : USA (Permanent Resident)

(in) : linkedin.com/in/m-d-patel

: www.letstrycatch.com

SKILLS

- Java
- Spring
- AngularJS
- NodeJS
- JSON
- Python
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- REST
- Maven
- Git/GitHub
- MySQL
- JSR 286 Portlet development
- Agile

TOOLS/LIBRARIES

- Visual Studio
- Eclipse
- JIRA
- SoapUI
- npm
- Apache Tomcat
- Pandas, NumPy
- IBM WebSphere Portal
- IBM Web Content Manager (WCM)
- IBM WebSphere Application Server (WAS)

CERTIFICATION

Full Stack Java Developer – Java-+ JSP + REST WS + Spring - course completion certification from udemy

PROFILE

Exceptionally passionate and self-driven Full Stack Java Developer with 3+ years of industry experience seeking for an opportunity that allow me to apply and enhance my critical thinking and problem-solving ability. Adept at developing and maintaining web applications. Agile at collaborating with team members to deliver effective results within deadlines.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

2019 - Present

- Translated wireframe of 'Food ordering app' into responsive, interactive web app using HTML/CSS, AngularJS, and JavaScript
- Developed UI for 'Covid-19 Tracker' Web Application
- Performed various web development related tasks for a variety of clients

Full Stack Developer

2018 - 2019

Augmetic Infinite LLP, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

- Built a web application for an online learning platform using Java, Maven, AngularJS, MySQL, JSON, Apache Tomcat, Git, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap
- Consulted with clients to determine user requirements and design solutions
- Analyzed performance and improved functionality of applications
- Trained and on-boarded new-hires on projects

Associate Software Developer

2017 - 2018

Streebo Inc, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

- Developed a web application comprising of Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate, AngularJS, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, SQL/OracleDB, JSON, RESTful API, Git
- Built a framework for PSCU, a credit union organization, to generate ondemand applications using IBM WebSphere Portal and NodeJS
- Managed content using IBM WCM and hosted it using IBM WAS
- Migrated PSCU-AdminConnect app from AngularJS to Angular2
- Implemented RESTful Web Services and JSR 286 Portlets

Research Intern

2016 - 2017

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

- Researched on 'Medical Coding: Evaluation and Ranking'
- Resolved ambiguities involved in medical data using 'Machine Learning' and 'Natural Language Processing' by adapting pre-trained word embeddings
- Accomplished data processing using Python, Pandas, NumPy
- Published work in BioNLP 2017

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Engineering Dharmsinh Desai University-Nadiad

2013 - 2017

GPA- 8.56/10

OTHER PROJECTS

Tech Store, an e-commerce web application *tech:* HTML5, CSS3 with Responsive design, NodeJS

Auction and Bidding System, a web application for auction

tech: HTML, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, C#, ASP.NET

Woman Security App, a location tracking application in case of an emergency *tech:* Android studio, Java